A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Division (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society, Program Officer, Office Files of Michael Lipsky FA595
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subject Files, 1965-2003; 6
  - International Human Rights Training for Indigenous Peoples, Ford Foundation Report, 2002 (Box 55, Folder 695)
  - Leadership for a Changing World (LCW) Awards Presentation, 2002 (Box 55, Folder 696)
  - Len Burman, The Urban Institute, 2001 (Box 55, Folder 697)
  - MAG Nominees, 2001 (Box 55, Folder 698)
  - National Association of Social Workers - Replication Seminar and Literature Review (Ford Foundation funded), 1993 (Box 55, Folder 699)
  - National Service Projects, 1999-2001 (Box 55, Folder 700)
  - Non-Profit Sector - Michael Lipsky Working Files, 1994-1998 (Box 55, Folder 701)
  - Philanthropy - Why Progressive Foundations Give Too Little to Too Many, The Nation, 1998 (Box 55, Folder 702)
  - Preparation for January 1992 Program Review (Governance and Public Policy), 1991-1992 (Box 55, Folder 703)
  - Participatory Research and Action (PRA) Evaluation by Michael Edwards, 1997 (Box 55, Folder 704)
  - Reflection Memo and Guidelines - September Meeting, 2001 (Box 55, Folder 705)
    Reflection memo guidelines attached to Merianne Sanchez Memo
  - Report, "Gendered Budget Work in the Americas: Selected Country Experience" by Natasha Borges Sugiyama Re: Ford Foundation Grantees, 2002 (Box 55, Folder 706)
  - Report, "Making Democracy Work" and List of Democracy Reform Organizations Supplement by Miles Rapoport, Report 016884, 2001 August (Box 55, Folder 707)
  - Cross Reference Sheet - "Race, Ethnicity and Access to Democracy: A Report to the Ford Foundation" by Penda D. Hair, 2001 May (Box 55, Folder 708)
  - State Fiscal Analysis Initiative Grants - Charles Stewart Mott Foundation Evaluation, 2001 (Box 55, Folder 709)
  - State Fiscal Analysis Initiative Grants - North Carolina Justice and Community Development, 2002 (Box 55, Folder 710)
  - State Fiscal Analysis Initiative Grants - United for a Fair Economy, 2002 (Box 55, Folder 711)
  - Workplans (FY 2002), Reflection Memorandum (2001), Annual Report Photography Memorandum from Michael Lipsky, 2001-2002 (Box 55, Folder 712)
  - State Fiscal Analysis Initiative - Desk File and Evaluation File, 1992-2000 (Box 56, Folder 713)
  - Economic Policy Institute (EPI) - Archive, 1991-2000 (Box 56, Folder 714)
  - Center on Budget and Policy Priorities, 1990-1992 (Box 56, Folder 715)
  - Citizen Participation Project, Sidney Verba, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 716)
  - Center for Responsive Politics, 1984-1992 (Box 56, Folder 717)
  - The Rights Approach to Local Public Management: Experiences from Brazil by Peter Spink, 1991-1992 (Box 56, Folder 718)
  - Professor Yash Ghai, Hong Kong University, Consultancy - Ethnic Conflict and Minority Rights in Relation to Asia, 1990-1992 (Box 57, Folder 719)
  - The American Experience with Legislative Education and Training: A Report to the Ford Foundation, Martha Wagner Weinberg, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 720)
  - Lynn Walker - Rights and Social Justice - Anthony Romero and Wayne Winborne, 1992-1993 (Box 57, Folder 721)
  - Jamie Cooper - Center for Policy Alternatives, 1991-1992 (Box 57, Folder 722)
  - First Worldwide Philanthropy Meeting, London, Convened by the Ford Foundation, 1997 October 16 (Box 57, Folder 723)
  - Report on London Philanthropy Meeting, 1997 (Box 57, Folder 724)
  - Improving Local Governance: A Conference of the Ford Foundation Local Governance Learning Group, Saint Paul, Minnesota, 2000 November 12-16 (Box 57, Folder 725)
  - Honoring Nations 2000: Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development, 1999-2000 (Box 57, Folder 726)
  - The Performance of the New York Police Department: Recommendations for Improvement, Citizens Budget Commission, 1993 January (Box 57, Folder 727)
  - The Performance of the New York City Fire Department: Recommendations for Improvement, Citizens Budget Commission, 1993 January (Box 57, Folder 728)
  - The Performance of the New York City Department of Correction: Recommendations for Improvement, Citizens Budget Commission, 1993 January (Box 58, Folder 729)
  - An Unbeatable Combination: More Police Strength and Lower Cost, Citizens Budget Commission, 1994 April (Box 58, Folder 730)
  - Professional Business Services in the New York City Economy, Citizens Budget Commission, 1995 July (Box 58, Folder 731)
  - A Study by the Citizens Budget Commission: Professional Business Services in the New York City Economy - Executive Summary, 1995 July (Box 58, Folder 732)
  - The Performance of the New York City Department of Sanitation: Recommendations for Improvement, Citizens Budget Commission, 1993 February (Box 58, Folder 733)
  - New York's State and Local Tax System: A Background Paper prepared for Citizens Budget Commission, Budget 2000 Project, 1995 December (Box 58, Folder 734)
  - Annotated Bibliography - Fiscal Policy Publications, 1992-2000 (Box 58, Folder 735)
  - Monitoring the Federal Budget in a Fiscal Adjustment Context: The Institute of Social-Economic Studies' (INESC) Work in Brazil, Aurelio Vianna, Jr., undated (Box 58, Folder 736)
  - Ford Foundation Staff Lists, undated (Box 58, Folder 737)
  - Social Development of Dalits and Tamil Nadu Govt. Budget: A Critique, Tamilnadu Peoples' Forum for Social Development, undated (Box 58, Folder 738)
  - Budget Analysis as Social Audit:Tamilnadu Experiences, 1996-2000, Tamilnadu Peoples' Forum for Social Development, undated (Box 58, Folder 739)
  - A Taste of Success: Examples of the Budget Work of NGOs, The International Budget Project, 2000 October (Box 58, Folder 740)
  - International Budget Project Conference, undated (Box 58, Folder 741)
    City Residents and Authorities Setting the Course for Cooperation: A Budget People Can Understand and Influence. Phase 2 Project Report for the period from September 1, 1999 to August 31, 2000
    Public Budget Transparency Scorecard in five Latin-American countries (Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Mexico, and Peru)
    Conference Schedule
  - Decentralisation From Above: Panchayati Raj in the 1990s, Vinod Vyasulu, Centre for Budget and Policy Studies, Bangalore, 2000 March (Box 58, Folder 742)
  - Budget Analysis and Policy Advocacy: Report from a National Workshop on Budget Analysis and Policy Advocacy in India, Abha Shankar and Mark Robinson, 2000 March (Box 58, Folder 743)
  - Correspondence with Alan Divack Regarding Contributions to Ford Foundation Archives, 2003 January 3 (Box 58, Folder 744)